<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blog | missionpenguin]]></title>
  <link href="http://krondor.github.com/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://krondor.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-15T16:55:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://krondor.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Kather]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[rkather@missionpenguin.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[So Long IT, Except Not Really]]></title>
    <link href="http://krondor.github.com/blog/2013/02/15/so-long-it-except-not-really/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-15T13:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://krondor.github.com/blog/2013/02/15/so-long-it-except-not-really</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow! How long has it been since I last posted?  It's been a hectic half year,
and now it's time for a little introspection.  I've changed careers, in a sense,
to embark on some new things.  For those of you who don't know me, I've spent a
long time in the trenches of enterprise IT.  It's been fun and rewarding, and by
no means a bad experience.  That being said I have noticed myself growing a bit
stir crazy of late.</p>

<p>So, what am I doing exactly?  While I've left my role as an IT Architect and
moved to the dark side.  That is Software Development, although I'm still doing
IT to an extent.  I've always worn multiple hats, so why should this be any
different.</p>

<p>It will be interesting to be on the other side of the IT/Software relationship
though.  I expect I'll have a good deal more to say on that dichotomy...</p>

<p>In the meantime, I'm hoping to get some posts out on some of the things I've
been playing with lately.  Should be some fun things to talk about around
Hadoop, R, MongoDB, Moodle, Juju, and MaaS.  That is if I ever find more time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[vendors: don't be a dick]]></title>
    <link href="http://krondor.github.com/blog/2012/06/15/vendors-dont-be-a-dick/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-15T10:29:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://krondor.github.com/blog/2012/06/15/vendors-dont-be-a-dick</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is probably going to feel a bit <em>ranty</em> and may have a bit of
 profanity, so if that annoys you I apologize and you might want to read
 something else for a bit.</p>

<p><strong>Vendors, I'm calling you out!  Stop being dicks!</strong></p>

<p>Don't get me wrong, I understand you can't run an IT endeavor without the
 vendors.  Even if you have a crack team it's all but inevitable.  You're going
 to run into some industry specific software, audit requirement, or the like
 that will force you to engage a vendor.  Do we really know everything about
 every niche solution the organization requires?  The entire thing can't
 effectively be DIY.  When dealing with vendors though, it's important to know
 that they are not your friend, and can actually be harmful.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='It&#8217;s a cut throat world, but
 here&#8217;s a tip; if you&#8217;re doing those shady things your time working with me will
 be short.'>
I've been in the field a long time, and I've seen a lot of things.  I've
 seen vendors attempt to bribe employees (fail and succeed).  I've seen vendors
 outright lie about their features or competitors.  Vendors have circumvented
 business processes for procurement.  They've harassed employees, sabotaged
 careers, and even bypassed whole departments.  It's a cut throat world, but
 here's a tip; if you're doing those shady things your time working with me will
 be short.
</span></p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Let's Talk About Joe</h3>

<p>I once worked for a place where we had a fake employee named Joe.  He had a
 voicemail and email address.  If you cold called us for sales, we would
 transfer you to Joe.  The IT director would review the calls and emails on
 occasion, but generally ignore most of the noise.  One day, after directing a
 call to Joe, we receive a call back.  The guy on the other end proceeds to tell
 us how Joe loved the idea of their product and asked what the next step was to
 cutting that PO.</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><em>Granted, fake employees make that sales job harder and might encourage this</em></p>

<h3>The Case of the Jogging CFO</h3>

<p>Once upon a time I was doing an in depth assessment of various spam filtering
 solutions.  I had built an in house box off of <a href="http://gentoo.org">Gentoo</a>,
 <a href="http://spamassassin.apache.org/">SpamAssassin</a>, <a href="http://www.ijs.si/software/amavisd/">Amavisd-new</a>,
 <a href="http://www.postfix.org">Postfix</a>, etc... and was comparing it against most
 of the industry leaders.  I was piping real spam we had received and real
 legitimate mail through each solution and comparing accuracy metrics. Upon the
 test conclusion, I informed the vendors that we were proceeding with our in
 house solution because it was more accurate than most of their offerings and
 cheaper.  The vendor lived near our CFO and saw him jogging one Sunday morning.
 He ran out of his house, ran down the CFO and proceeded to tell him what a
 horrible mistake we were making and how we were going to cost them a fortune
 and loss of brand reputation.  The CFO queried me on the  incident and after
 showing him our test methodology and results, that vendor made it to our
 blacklist of companies to never do business with.</p>

<h3>Churning about in the Rumor Mill</h3>

<p>In another instance, a particular vendor had the ear of a certain CTO.
 When the vendors bid on a project appeared to be losing favor for a competing
 solution, the vendor began to spread some rumors like, "a key IT engineer was
 interviewing with a competitor", and subsequently "his recommendations should
 be suspect due to said interviews". The CTO in this case, chose to error on the
 side of caution removing the engineer from the project.  The vendor did not win
 the bid.</p>

<p>IT is an incestuous industry, and we all share connections.  It's easy
 for rumors to circulate and can be quite damaging.</p>

<h3>They don't support Syslog</h3>

<p>A final story of a vendor, in this case spreading misinformation.  In another
 engagement several vendors were being considered for a solution.  One vendor
 was quite aggressive and had learned who the competing company was in the bid.
 Armed with this information the vendor began to spread <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear,_uncertainty_and_doubt">FUD</a>
 about the competition.  It started simple enough, did you see these earning
 statements?  What about this whitepaper or study?  How about this key employee
 leaving for greener pastures?  Eventually culminating in lies, in this case
 the product does not support syslog.  A quick check of the website features
 list would have debunked that quickly, let alone our test process, or interviews
 with other customers.</p>

<p>I could go on as I'm sure many of you have your own stories.  For the sake of
 brevity let's move forward.  What does it all mean?</p>

<h3>So Vendors Are Evil?</h3>

<p>Vendor's aren't evil per se, but they're not your friend either.  A lot of my
 colleagues live by their vendors.  They're fanboys and girls for a product.  I
 get it, you've invested time and effort in that product.  It's human nature for
 bias on something you've become vested (see the excellent <a href="http://blog.testfreaks.com/information/anatomy-fanboy/">Anatomy of a Fanboy</a> post).</p>

<p>You've certified, justified the use and need, and maybe things have gone well
 for you. Vendors can be helpful.  They brought in resources to train you, they
 helped with the deployment, and they've held your hand and given you comfort.
 If something were to break, you have a <em>neck to wring</em> as the saying goes. You
 can even make a good career on backing your vendor.  There's also something to
 be said for that healthy working relationship.</p>

<p>Let's not kid ourselves though, there's no altruism here.  They're out to make
 a profit.  At the moment you're profitable, but as you stress that relation
 maybe they're not so engaging and helpful.  Perhaps the account manager is
 focused on the long term and not worried about how much resources they're
 investing, but perhaps not.</p>

<p>My advise to the IT professional is this.  Don't be a puppet.  Stop making
 excuses for a vendor deficiency and own it.  Deal with it, and move on.  Keep
 in mind that vendor has a focus on profit, and don't be afraid to test
 that relationship and compare to other solutions.  View vendors as providing a
 service.  You want to hold the keys and you should dictate the terms.  It's not
 about hurting feelings, it's about business.</p>

<p>My advise to the vendors is this.  Let your product stand on its own.  Show me
 your value without resorting to the things above, and if you can't deliver on a
 requirement tell me.  I'd rather know what I'm getting into ahead of time, than
 hate our relationship down the road.  Losing one bullet point in a comparison
 matrix does not mean we won't pick your solution.  However, misrepresenting
 the solution or resorting to nastiness will guarantee a seat on the loser pile.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[two factor and lastpass]]></title>
    <link href="http://krondor.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/two-factor-and-lastpass/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-09T12:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://krondor.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/two-factor-and-lastpass</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You need multi-factor authentication.  Passwords are no longer good enough.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='You shouldn&#8217;t trust your password.  It has probably been
 compromised.'>
How secure is your password?  If we've learned anything over the years on the
 Internet it's this. You shouldn't trust your password.  It has probably been
 compromised.  Even if it hasn't, you might as well treat it as such.  These
 are strong words, but it's not an illogical stance to take.  How good are your
 password practices?  Do you mix case, use alphanumeric characters, spaces, or
 symbols?  Is your password over 14 characters long?  Do you change them on a
 regular basis?  Do you recycle them?  Is it based on a dictionary word or
 known item from your life?
</span></p>

<p>Chances are you are not doing at least a few of the points above.  Which is why
 for years I've been an advocate of password managers.  I'm presently using
 <a href="http://lastpass.com">LastPass</a>, which is the genesis for this post.  I've
 used quite a few of these in my day (most recently
 <a href="http://docs.kde.org/stable/en/kdeutils/kwallet/index.html">kwallet</a>
 and <a href="http://keepassx.org">KeePassX</a>.  Some are better than others, but almost
 any is better than nothing.  LastPass, however, has particularly impressed me.
  So what makes it so special, and how can it help keep us more secure?</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Why LastPass?</h2>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/LastPassLogo329x40.png"></p>

<p>Like any good password manager, LastPass holds the keys to your life in an
 encrypted vault.  You manage entries in the vault and lock it with a master
 password.  The vault can generate random passwords for you and assign those
 to entries.  This is all par for the course as these things go, and don't
 necessarily stand out on their own.</p>

<p>So what makes LastPass so good;</p>

<ul>
<li>Cloud Synchronization</li>
<li>Client Side Encryption</li>
<li>Multi-factor Authentication Support</li>
<li>One Time Use Passwords</li>
<li>Browser Plugin Support (Chrome/Firefox/Internet Explorer/Opera/Safari/Others)</li>
<li>Multiple Platform Support (Android/iOS/Linux/OSX/Windows/Others)</li>
<li>More Than Passwords (Form Data/Notes)</li>
<li>Price (LastPass is free for use outside of mobile clients)</li>
<li>Password Sharing with Friends</li>
<li>Import/Export Utilities</li>
<li>Phishing Protection</li>
</ul>


<p>In particular, the cloud synchronization has been immense.  Knowing that all my
 computers can utilize the same password vault, across operating systems and
 browsers has been huge.  With that in place you no longer need to remember
 your logins, and with that you can generate random passwords uniquely for all
 sites.  Now you've compartmentalized your exposure.  If someone were to
 compromise the account you made on that one blog about snorkeling, you wouldn't
 be at risk that they could use that same password for your bank.  You've
 mitigated your risk just in this one act.</p>

<p>So that's great but this online synchronization sounds like it might not be
 that great an idea.</p>

<h3>Cloud Synchronization</h3>

<p>LastPass syncs your vault to their online service.</p>

<p>That is a scary statement, and immediately had me worried when I saw the
 service.  How can I trust that their backend is secure?  If it worries you to
 have your password vault propagated across the Internet, don't worry it means
 your self preservation instinct is working correctly.  LastPass works around
 this basic issue of trust through the use of a
 <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salted_hash">salted hash</a>.
 Effectively this means that passwords and form data you populate into your
 vault, are encrypted client side and only the resultant hash with salt is sent
 to their online system.  LastPass doesn't know the vault contents of its users
 only the hashes.</p>

<p>This is an important point because it nullifies one of the biggest issues with
 password based authentication.  The password storage.  You could be the poster
 child for security password best practices, and when the website you're
 visiting gets hacked (and left your password cleartext in their database),
 your password has been compromised.  This sounds trivial, but you might be
 surprised <a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/gawker-hack-release-notes.html">how</a>
 <a href="http://www.reddit.com/comments/usqe/reddits_streak_of_bad_luck_continues/cuugl">many</a>
 <a href="http://www.itworld.com/security/249460/hacked-microsoft-online-store-saved-passwords-plain-text">popular</a>
 sites haven't learned their lesson about storing clear text passwords.  I
 suppose I should also elaborate that the use of a salt is key here.  Even
 passwords that are hashed are vulnerable to
 <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rainbow_table">rainbow tables</a>,
 and these are increasingly pre-generated for the taking.  The salt nullifies
 this leaving the stolen password vault only vulnerable to the venerable (and
 much more time consuming) offline dictionary attack.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>"This thing is secure every way you can imagine. And it's simple,"</p><footer><strong>Steve Gibson,</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r9Q_anb7pwg&amp;feature=player_embedded'>Security Now 256: LastPass Security</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>So that's a pretty bold statement, and given the context of the conversation on
 that linked episode I wouldn't put too much weight in that.  However,  it does
 seem nice that LastPass has a good level of industry analysis and commenting
 by security folks.  It's not open source, and that takes away a degree of
 trust in my mind, but the model does seem sound.</p>

<p>Now I should point out that you can accomplish similar ends with other solutions
 like KeePassX and Dropbox.  However, there is a level of trust in your
 synchronization mechanism and an ease of use factor to consider.  Dropbox, in
 particular, hasn't had a stellar <a href="http://blog.dropbox.com/?p=821">security record</a>.
 There are other options (some of them <a href="https://www.box.com/">more secure</a>),
 but with them you may incur costs or complexity which directly impacts the
 platforms and sync options you have.</p>

<p>I could probably go on, but let's get to the next point.</p>

<h3>Multi-factor authentication</h3>

<p>The security mechanisms in place around your password vault are all well and
 good, but they're not enough.  The vault can still be attacked, and now that
 it's online and synchronized between all the computers and mobile devices you
 won means its <strong>much</strong> more exposed.  In fact, a more likely hacking avenue,
 might not be a dictionary attack against your vault.  It's easy to become lazy
 and security can be annoying.  It's a PITA to always have to authenticate to
 your vault, and it's really easy to check that remember my password button.
 Sure you've got a password on your workstation, laptop, and phone right?
 Maybe, it's not the remember my password button, but the keylogger on the
 malware you didn't know you had?  You've patched <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/adriankingsleyhughes/2012/05/06/emergency-flash-update-fixes-security-vulnerability-used-to-hijack-windows-pcs/">
 flash</a>
 recently right?</p>

<p>There needs to be another barrier on your online identity, and LastPass has you
 covered.
 <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-factor_authentication">Multi-factor authentication</a>
 provides that second level of authentication to make the system that much
 harder to compromise.  LastPass has included support for a variety of
 additional authentication mechanisms.  Yubikey, Google Authenticator, and USB
 key options exist.  The idea here is that even if your password is compromised
 attackers would still need to enter the second form of authentication
 (usually a numeric PIN that changes every 60 seconds), that old adage something
 you have and something you know.</p>

<p><img src="/images/googleauth_authenticate.png"></p>

<p>Multi-factor can be a pain, but it's an additional piece of mind that puts a
 significant barrier on your identity theft.  If you look at the most
 significant hacking targets (government, banking, online game platforms
 (steam, battle.net)) you'll note a generally strong uptake of multi-factor
 authentication.  This is because it is quite effective (although that didn't
 stop the
 <a href="http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2011/08/details_of_the.html">RSA hack</a>,
 but that's a different discussion).
 <a href="https://code.google.com/p/google-authenticator/">Mobile authenticators on smartphones</a>,
 <a href="http://helpdesk.lastpass.com/security-options/sesame-multifactor-authentication-with-a-usb-thumb-drive/">USB keys</a> (<em>premium feature</em>),
 <a href="http://www.yubico.com/yubikey-neo">NFC</a>, and the like have done a great deal
 to make this accessible and easy to live with for everyday usage.  A word of
 caution, you'll note in the screenshot the checkbox to <strong>not require</strong> two
 factor for this computer.  You can get into the same <em>remember my password</em>
 quandary with indiscriminate checking of that box.</p>

<p>What's the point of two factor if you disable it?</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/tryit.jpg"></p>

<p>So I could go on and on about the other nifty things.  Sharing passwords with a
 friend/spouse/associate without actually giving them the password or access to
 the vault.  How about, one time use passwords for that time you want to see
 your vault at Starbucks, but don't trust the computer to not log your
 keystrokes?  Or how about the on screen keyboard for your password entry
 (again fighting keyloggers).  Instead, I'll just leave it to this.</p>

<p><strong>LastPass is free and good.  Try it, you'll like it!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[solarized]]></title>
    <link href="http://krondor.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/solarized/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-08T14:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://krondor.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/solarized</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/solarize_things.jpg"></p>

<p>This blog is now <strong><a href="http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized">Solarized!</a></strong>.  I made
 the change today, after having already moved to this color scheme in my shell,
 editor, etc... I'm really enjoying it on my desktop, so I thought why not the
 blog?  The color scheme is supposed to help reduce eye strain while maintaining
 nice contrast of content.  That sounds about right for me, living in this sea of
 florescent light powered cubicles.</p>

<p>I elected to use the light variant of solarized for the blog content and scheme
 and use the dark solarized variant for code snippets.  I think it's working out
 kind of well, but probably needs some tweaks.</p>

<p>The link above has all the gory details, whereas I'll keep this post a short one
 and just dump out the gist of the color scheme's SASS CSS.</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/2638348.js?file=_colors.scss'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>$header-bg: #fdf6e3;
$page-bg:  #002b36;
$footer-bg: #eee8d5;
$sidebar-bg: #eee8d5;
$main-bg: #fdf6e3;
$title-color: #586e75;
$subtitle-color: #93a1a1;
$text-color: #657b83;
$text-color-light: #839496;
$footer-bg-back: linear-gradient($footer-bg, darken($footer-bg, 8));

/* To use the light Solarized highlighting theme uncomment the following line */
$solarized: dark;
</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Happy Hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[chrome frame]]></title>
    <link href="http://krondor.github.com/blog/2012/02/09/chrome-frame/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-09T15:27:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://krondor.github.com/blog/2012/02/09/chrome-frame</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So having spent some time fumbling around in <a href="http://octopress.org">octopress</a>,
 I've made my first modification.  Internet Explorer is a constant source of
 pain when theming websites.  As this is my personal blog there isn't really a
 reason to be particularly friendly to Internet Explorer, and so I thought why
 not prompt my visitors to install
 <a href="http://code.google.com/chrome/chromeframe/">Chrome Frame</a>.</p>

<p>Chrome Frame effectively replaces the rendering engine of IE with Google Chrome
 through a plugin for IE.  In effect users who install it are now running
 Chrome, and as such are treated with properly working CSS/HTML5/JS support.
 Which now means they can see my nicely rendered 3D logo all in CSS courtesy of
 <a href="%22http://www.markdott.com/2011/01/05/3d-text-using-just-css/">Mark Otto</a>.
  Wonderful, but how to get my visitors to install Chrome Frame?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>Once Chrome Frame has been installed the user-agent header can report its
 presence.</p>

<p><code>apache Chrome Frame User-Agent Example
Mozilla/4.0 (compatible; MSIE 6.0; Windows NT 5.1; SV1; chromeframe/11.0.660.0)
</code></p>

<p>Given that we can detect if Chrome Frame is installed it's possible to
 selectively prompt visitors to install it for IE if they haven't done this
 already.  There's a great guide on the process on the Chromium site
 <a href="http://www.chromium.org/developers/how-tos/chrome-frame-getting-started">here</a>.
 However, I didn't want to just go about pasting the scripts snippet into my
 HTML body here.  I mean that's why I'm using Octopress and not just native HTML
 right?  Let's programmatically decide if we should push our IE friends toward
 the Chrome light.</p>

<p>So how to inject the Chrome Frame javascript in Octopress?  Let's begin with a
 configuration directive to test against in our _config.yml.</p>

<p>``` yml _config.yml chrome frame directive</p>

<h1>Chrome Frame Prompt</h1>

<p>chromeframe: true
```</p>

<p>Now that we have a clause to test against Octopress can decide on whether or not
 to build the chrome frame code into the site.  The only piece left was to
 decide where the code should reside.  Octopress is pretty good at maintaining a
 custom directory structure for modifications to the base.  It's a good idea to
 keep that structure so updates to the core are easier to maintain.  Head.html
 seems to be the logical place for onload scripts to me, so I made my custom
 changes there.</p>

<p><code>bash chrome frame custom html file location
/home/myuser/octopress/source/_includes/custom/head.html
</code></p>

<p>Now I declare when the code should be included given our config.yml directive
 using <a href="http://liquidmarkup.orgi">Liquid</a> markup syntax with an if
 block for site.chromeframe.</p>

<p>I paste in the chrome frame installation script from the Chromium example linked
 above and modify it for my needs, and we're almost good to go. I really didn't
 change much.  I opted to use overlay mode for the prompt because I'm not quite
 sure where I'd like to inject it inline.  The only issue with overlay (besides
 annoyance to my visitors), is that it doesn't seem to work on IE7 and earlier.
 I insert a <meta> to the head to enable chrome frame for my pages content
 (this would normally be done in the http server config, but as I don't have
 access to that...).</p>

<p><code>html meta tag to enable chrome frame
&lt;meta http-equiv="X-UA-Compatible" content="chrome=1"&gt;
</code></p>

<p>Giving us the final product of...</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><figcaption><span>[final customized head.html with modifications] (head.html)</span> <a href='/downloads/code/head.html'>download</a></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='html'><span class='line'><span class="c">&lt;!--Fonts from Google&quot;s Web font directory at http://google.com/webfonts --&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;link</span> <span class="na">href=</span><span class="s">&quot;http://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=PT+Serif:regular,italic,bold,bolditalic&quot;</span> <span class="na">rel=</span><span class="s">&quot;stylesheet&quot;</span> <span class="na">type=</span><span class="s">&quot;text/css&quot;</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;link</span> <span class="na">href=</span><span class="s">&quot;http://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=PT+Sans:regular,italic,bold,bolditalic&quot;</span> <span class="na">rel=</span><span class="s">&quot;stylesheet&quot;</span> <span class="na">type=</span><span class="s">&quot;text/css&quot;</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>{% if site.chromeframe %}
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c">&lt;!--[if IE]&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">    &lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;X-UA-Compatible&quot; content=&quot;chrome=1&quot;&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">    &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">      src=&quot;http://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/chrome-frame/1/CFInstall.min.js&quot;&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">    &lt;/script&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">    &lt;style&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">      .chromeFrameInstallDefaultStyle {</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">        width: 100%</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">        border: 5px solid blue;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">      }</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">    &lt;/style&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">    &lt;script&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">      window.attachEvent(&quot;onload&quot;, function() {</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">        CFInstall.check({</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">          mode: &quot;overlay&quot;,</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">        });</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">      });</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">    &lt;/script&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">  &lt;![endif]--&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>{% endif %}
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>So far so good, now we can deploy and test;</p>

<p><code>ruby build and deploy site changes
rake generate
rake deploy
</code></p>

<p>Success! My IE visitors will now be greeted with an overlay prompt enticing them
 to install chrome frame.</p>

<p><img src="/images/chrome_frame_overlay.png"></p>

<p>Now if only they'd install it (or even better just get a full Chrome or Firefox
 browser in the first place).  Most importantly I learned how to control a
 feature of my site by manipulating _config.yml and custom overrides to the
 stock templates.  Fun times!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
