<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: vendors | missionpenguin]]></title>
  <link href="http://krondor.github.com/blog/categories/vendors/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://krondor.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-15T16:55:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://krondor.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Kather]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[rkather@missionpenguin.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[vendors: don't be a dick]]></title>
    <link href="http://krondor.github.com/blog/2012/06/15/vendors-dont-be-a-dick/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-15T10:29:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://krondor.github.com/blog/2012/06/15/vendors-dont-be-a-dick</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is probably going to feel a bit <em>ranty</em> and may have a bit of
 profanity, so if that annoys you I apologize and you might want to read
 something else for a bit.</p>

<p><strong>Vendors, I'm calling you out!  Stop being dicks!</strong></p>

<p>Don't get me wrong, I understand you can't run an IT endeavor without the
 vendors.  Even if you have a crack team it's all but inevitable.  You're going
 to run into some industry specific software, audit requirement, or the like
 that will force you to engage a vendor.  Do we really know everything about
 every niche solution the organization requires?  The entire thing can't
 effectively be DIY.  When dealing with vendors though, it's important to know
 that they are not your friend, and can actually be harmful.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='It&#8217;s a cut throat world, but
 here&#8217;s a tip; if you&#8217;re doing those shady things your time working with me will
 be short.'>
I've been in the field a long time, and I've seen a lot of things.  I've
 seen vendors attempt to bribe employees (fail and succeed).  I've seen vendors
 outright lie about their features or competitors.  Vendors have circumvented
 business processes for procurement.  They've harassed employees, sabotaged
 careers, and even bypassed whole departments.  It's a cut throat world, but
 here's a tip; if you're doing those shady things your time working with me will
 be short.
</span></p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Let's Talk About Joe</h3>

<p>I once worked for a place where we had a fake employee named Joe.  He had a
 voicemail and email address.  If you cold called us for sales, we would
 transfer you to Joe.  The IT director would review the calls and emails on
 occasion, but generally ignore most of the noise.  One day, after directing a
 call to Joe, we receive a call back.  The guy on the other end proceeds to tell
 us how Joe loved the idea of their product and asked what the next step was to
 cutting that PO.</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><em>Granted, fake employees make that sales job harder and might encourage this</em></p>

<h3>The Case of the Jogging CFO</h3>

<p>Once upon a time I was doing an in depth assessment of various spam filtering
 solutions.  I had built an in house box off of <a href="http://gentoo.org">Gentoo</a>,
 <a href="http://spamassassin.apache.org/">SpamAssassin</a>, <a href="http://www.ijs.si/software/amavisd/">Amavisd-new</a>,
 <a href="http://www.postfix.org">Postfix</a>, etc... and was comparing it against most
 of the industry leaders.  I was piping real spam we had received and real
 legitimate mail through each solution and comparing accuracy metrics. Upon the
 test conclusion, I informed the vendors that we were proceeding with our in
 house solution because it was more accurate than most of their offerings and
 cheaper.  The vendor lived near our CFO and saw him jogging one Sunday morning.
 He ran out of his house, ran down the CFO and proceeded to tell him what a
 horrible mistake we were making and how we were going to cost them a fortune
 and loss of brand reputation.  The CFO queried me on the  incident and after
 showing him our test methodology and results, that vendor made it to our
 blacklist of companies to never do business with.</p>

<h3>Churning about in the Rumor Mill</h3>

<p>In another instance, a particular vendor had the ear of a certain CTO.
 When the vendors bid on a project appeared to be losing favor for a competing
 solution, the vendor began to spread some rumors like, "a key IT engineer was
 interviewing with a competitor", and subsequently "his recommendations should
 be suspect due to said interviews". The CTO in this case, chose to error on the
 side of caution removing the engineer from the project.  The vendor did not win
 the bid.</p>

<p>IT is an incestuous industry, and we all share connections.  It's easy
 for rumors to circulate and can be quite damaging.</p>

<h3>They don't support Syslog</h3>

<p>A final story of a vendor, in this case spreading misinformation.  In another
 engagement several vendors were being considered for a solution.  One vendor
 was quite aggressive and had learned who the competing company was in the bid.
 Armed with this information the vendor began to spread <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear,_uncertainty_and_doubt">FUD</a>
 about the competition.  It started simple enough, did you see these earning
 statements?  What about this whitepaper or study?  How about this key employee
 leaving for greener pastures?  Eventually culminating in lies, in this case
 the product does not support syslog.  A quick check of the website features
 list would have debunked that quickly, let alone our test process, or interviews
 with other customers.</p>

<p>I could go on as I'm sure many of you have your own stories.  For the sake of
 brevity let's move forward.  What does it all mean?</p>

<h3>So Vendors Are Evil?</h3>

<p>Vendor's aren't evil per se, but they're not your friend either.  A lot of my
 colleagues live by their vendors.  They're fanboys and girls for a product.  I
 get it, you've invested time and effort in that product.  It's human nature for
 bias on something you've become vested (see the excellent <a href="http://blog.testfreaks.com/information/anatomy-fanboy/">Anatomy of a Fanboy</a> post).</p>

<p>You've certified, justified the use and need, and maybe things have gone well
 for you. Vendors can be helpful.  They brought in resources to train you, they
 helped with the deployment, and they've held your hand and given you comfort.
 If something were to break, you have a <em>neck to wring</em> as the saying goes. You
 can even make a good career on backing your vendor.  There's also something to
 be said for that healthy working relationship.</p>

<p>Let's not kid ourselves though, there's no altruism here.  They're out to make
 a profit.  At the moment you're profitable, but as you stress that relation
 maybe they're not so engaging and helpful.  Perhaps the account manager is
 focused on the long term and not worried about how much resources they're
 investing, but perhaps not.</p>

<p>My advise to the IT professional is this.  Don't be a puppet.  Stop making
 excuses for a vendor deficiency and own it.  Deal with it, and move on.  Keep
 in mind that vendor has a focus on profit, and don't be afraid to test
 that relationship and compare to other solutions.  View vendors as providing a
 service.  You want to hold the keys and you should dictate the terms.  It's not
 about hurting feelings, it's about business.</p>

<p>My advise to the vendors is this.  Let your product stand on its own.  Show me
 your value without resorting to the things above, and if you can't deliver on a
 requirement tell me.  I'd rather know what I'm getting into ahead of time, than
 hate our relationship down the road.  Losing one bullet point in a comparison
 matrix does not mean we won't pick your solution.  However, misrepresenting
 the solution or resorting to nastiness will guarantee a seat on the loser pile.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
